let's look at the solution for our
control dependence quiz in a pipeline we
know how many instructions are taking
branches we don't really care that it's
a 10 stage pipeline what we care about
is that the branch is a result in the
six stage and that everything else works
smoothly
so the actual CPI will be one per
instruction this happens for branches
and all the other instructions plus for
every taken branch and that happens 25%
of the instructions we have a penalty of
five cycles why because when we resolve
the branch in the sixth stage they have
already been five stages worth of
instructions that we fetched from the
wrong place and we have to throw them
away so following a branch like this
there will be five cycles in which we
don't finish anything so we spend one
cycle per instruction and for 25% of
instructions we spend additional five
cycles for that instruction basically
there are five empty cycles after it if
you multiply this out you get 2.25 as
you can see this CPI is very far from
the ideal our processor is less than
half as fast as it would be without the
taken branches